http://www.karuna.org/privacy-policy

|CONTACT
Our WorkOur ProjectsAbout UsGet InvolvedJoin a campaignChristmas CampaignCoronavirus CrisisFundraise for usLeave a gift in your will
DONATE
Our WorkOur ProjectsAbout UsGet InvolvedJoin a campaignChristmas CampaignCoronavirus CrisisFundraise for usLeave a gift in your will
Legal Information
We are firmly committed to protecting your privacy and aim to be clear when we collect your information and use it only as you would reasonably expect. In this Privacy Policy, “We”, “Us” and “Our” mean Karuna Trust registered in England and Wales, charity number 327461. Our registered office is 72 Holloway Road, London, N7 8JG.
Contents
How we use Personal InformationOur legal basis for processing personal information How we collect personal information The personal information that we collect How we may share personal informationHow long we keep personal informationYour rightsChanges to this policyContact
How we use Personal Information
We will not use your personal information unless we have first told you how we will use it or it is obvious how we will use it.
We collect and use personal
information for:
FundraisingProcessing donations Supporter development and administrationProcessing general enquiriesVolunteer recruitmentVolunteer administrationGovernance and Trustee managementEmployee recruitmentEmployee administration
Our legal basis for processing personal information
Our lawful basis for the purposes that we process personal information is consent, for the performance of a contract or for our legitimate interests.
The law allows us to collect and use personal data if it is necessary for our legitimate business interest and so long as its use is fair, balanced and does not unduly impact your rights. In many situations, the best approach for our members is to process personal data because of our legitimate interests, rather than consent.
We will ask for your consent to send you updates about our work via post, email, telephone, or text messages. You can withdraw consent for this at any time.
We may also share your personal information where we are compelled by law to do so.
We process employee personal information to meet our legal obligations as an employer.
How we collect personal information
We collect personal information from you directly through our website, paper forms and sometimes over the telephone.
We may collect information about the software on your computer (your browser version etc.) and your IP address (your connection with the internet) to improve your interaction with the Website and for our records. This may happen automatically without your being aware of it.
We may use cookies (small text files which we and other website operators store on your computer when you visit our websites) to deliver a better and more personalised interaction. They enable us to recognise you when you return to the Website, store information about your preferences, and improve the way your searches are processed. They also enable us to generate statistics about the number of visitors we have and how they use the Website and the internet. You can set your browser to reject our cookies if you wish (you should consult your browser help section for details), but this might restrict your use of the website and other websites.
The personal information that we collect
The type and quantity of information we collect and how we use it depends on why you are providing it.
For fundraising and processing donations we will collect:
Your nameYour contact detailsYour mailing preferencesYour bank or credit card details
For supporter development we may also collect:
Your interestsYour date of birthYour occupationInformation about your demographicInformation about your specialitiesInformation about your qualifications
For volunteer recruitment and administration, we will collect:
Your nameYour contact detailsYour employment historyYour interests or information which may support your applicationYour mailing preferencesYour tax details, date of birth and photo IDYour bank detailsYour medical information, which is optionalYour likeness in an image or video, which is optionalYour unspent criminal record offences under the Rehabiliation of Offenders Act 1974
For employee recruitment and administration, we will collect:
Your name Your contact detailsYour employment historyYour interests or information which may support your applicationYour mailing preferencesYour tax details, date of birth and photo IDYour bank detailsYour gender, nationality, ethnicity, religion and if you have a disability insofar as we have a legal obligation to do soYour spiritual or religious preferences, which are optional and only recorded if volunteered at the point of applicationYour medical information, which is optionalYour spent and/or unspent criminal record offences, under the Rehabilitation of Offenders Act 1974, depending on the role applied for
How we may share personal information
We may share some of your personal information with organisations that carry out processing operations on our behalf, such as web services companies and mailing organisations. We carry out checks on these companies before we work with them and put a contract in place that sets out our expectations and requirements, especially regarding how they manage the personal information that we give to them.
We do not sell or share personal information to third parties for the purposes of marketing. But, if we run an event in partnership with another named organisation your details may need to be shared with them. We will be very clear what will happen to your personal information if you register for such an event.
We will only ever share your data in other circumstances if we have your explicit and informed consent, or we are required by law to do so.
How long we keep personal information
We will only keep personal information for as long as we have a valid reason for keeping it. After that we delete or dispose of the information securely.
If you are a donor or are considering becoming one:
Information collected by our fundraisers is kept for the length of that appeal and then destroyed unless you sign up to become a donor.Donor information is kept on record for the length of time you are a supporter and then 6 months post leaving in case of any queries relating to your support. Financial information relating to donor contributions is kept for the length of time you support us and then 7 years post ceasing your donations to comply with UK Tax laws. Please note that we do not store any Credit or Debit Card details once they have been processed.
If you are a volunteer or have applied to be one:
Volunteer application information is kept for the length of the application process and destroyed if the applicant does not proceed to become a volunteer, unless consent is given to retain information for the purposes of future applications.Contact details of the individuals who have consented to join our volunteer recruitment mailing list will be kept and may be removed at any time, either by unsubscribing via the emails or by contacting the office. Any volunteer photos or videos given to us with prior consent for the purposes of recruitment will be kept indefinitely which will be stated clearly on the consent form.Accepted volunteer information is kept indefinitely to ensure volunteer needs are met and available if the applicant decides to volunteer for another appeal at a later date.
If you are an employee or have applied to be one:
Employment application information is kept for the length of the application process and destroyed if the applicant does not proceed to become an employee of Karuna.Employee information is kept for the duration of their employment and 6 years after employment ceases in accordance with UK Employment Law.
Your rights
You have a right to know what personal data we hold, who we acquired it from, how we process it, the logic involved in any automatic processing, and who we disclose it to.
You have a right to ask us not to process your personal data for direct marketing purposes.
You have a right to ask us not to make decisions based solely on the automatic processing of your personal information.
You have a right to ask us not to process your personal information in a way that is likely to cause unwarranted and substantial damage or distress.
You have a right to ask us to erase your personal information.
These statutory rights are qualified by exceptions and exemptions.
To exercise any of these rights, please contact us using the address below.
You can find out more about your rights from the Information Commissioner, who regulates data protection and privacy. The Information Commissioner’s website is www.ico.org.uk
Changes to this policy
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on our website or by contacting you directly.
Contact
Please feel free to contact us with any questions, comments or queries regarding this Privacy Policy. All questions should be directed to the Data Protection contact at info@karuna.org or 020 7700 3434
CONTACT
Useful Links
Our WorkOur ProjectsAbout Us
Fundraise for UsLeave a Gift in Your WillJoin the Team
TrusteesMeet the TeamFinancials
FAQsPrivacy PolicySafeguarding Policy
The Karuna Trust
72 Holloway Road
London, N7 8JG
The Karuna Trust is a charity registered in England and Wales no. 327461 and a company limited by guarantee registered in England No. 2132178
Keep In Touch
×
It is essential that Karuna can communicate with our supporters in order to ensure that the work we do is as effective as possible. Unlike other charities, we won’t bombard you. We will write to you twice a year with important updates on how your donation is making a difference and may call or email you from time to time to let you know about new events at Karuna. That’s it. You can change your preferences at any time by getting in touch.
Close
Submit
